In this lesson, you'll learn about CHA GPT memory is white matters and how to use it effectively as a developer.
So CHA GPT memory allows the model to remember information between chats,
like a preference on going projects your interests or your code contacts.
It's different from the normal chat when everything resets when you close the conversation.
So, but with memory CHA GPT can remember, so who are you, what you're working on,
what is your coding style, or those you use, what is the technical stack,
what previous code snippets of task you discuss.
So, this makes your interaction more personalized and efficient over time.
Especially if you use CHA GPT for coding the bug in a teaching, so memory helps save time.
So, we don't need to rex playing the same scenes again and again.
And you shouldn't always update the custom instructions, so it can just remember it
from your conversations. So, let me show you how to enable it, just go to settings,
personalization, and you will see right here is a memory, you can click learn more to read it,
to read more about it, and you can click manage to see all your memories, memory items for
your version, it's quite limited, I don't remember exactly my bit 2030 items, and if it's full,
so you can always check and delete something. Also, like you can enable some features,
you can let CHA GPT save and use memories when responding, it's when you don't want to
care what is in your memory, so you can allow this function. Otherwise, you can edit manually,
right here, sorry, you can edit manually, so it can also, it can only take it from a chart,
but I will show you one live card, or we can edit manually. Okay, the next one is you can let
CHA GPT use your memories in the different charts, I recommend you to use it as true,
and I will show you how to manually ask CHA GPT to save something, so save in memory
that I don't know how to deploy applications. So you see CHA GPT updated memory, so we can always
update it, and if I create a new chart and I will ask, what is my expertise in deploying apps?
You have told me that you don't know how to deploy applications yet, you haven't indicated any
experience, so you see it works, it's a hack, how to remember information between the charts.
So let's talk quickly, what's the difference from custom instructions?
Memory is dynamic, it updates over time as a chart, so CHA GPT decides by
himself what's stored in memory, it can remember what you tell and use it automatically later,
so you can also say, remember it or forget this information from a chart and it is also deleted
or added, or you can ask updated. It helps model know what your current context habits and project
automatically result manual updating information. Custom instructions is static information you have
in your settings, right here, this is what we added in one of previous lessons, it's static,
it's like a fixed profile, where you are, how you'd like CHA GPT response, it doesn't change
unless you added it manually. So in general, to wrap up, so you can keep your memory clean and
updated, always by going to settings, personalization, manage and just delete items is not
actual anymore, especially if you are on pre-plan, because it's limited and avoid always
stored in some sensitive data like passwords or tokens in memory. Okay, I hope this lesson was
useful for you and see you in the next one.